Samuel K. Wolfe

 $530\text{-}638\text{-}5831 \mid wolfesamk@gmail.com \mid swolfe@ucdavis.edu \\ https://www.linkedin.com/in/wolfesamk \mid GitHub Portfolio: https://github.com/wolfesamk \\$

PROFILE

Systems Administrator with eleven years of experience providing technical oversight, management, system implementation and installation, and analytical support to managers, supervisors, staff, and customers. In-depth knowledge and skill performing long-distance strategic planning, system hardware and software research, network and system consultation, configuration, administration, and programming.

NOTABLE ACHIEVEMENTS

- 2023 Business Analytics Competition CSUS Center for Business Analytics "Should This Loan be Approved or Denied?" Machine Learning Predictive Modeling Using SBA National Data.
 - Team Leader, three-person team. After assigning roles and duties I was responsible for dimension reduction, data transformation, Logit models Lasso, Ridge, and ElasticNet.
- Developed API and script to clean up GSM Deskpro system of CRM users not associated with a
 ticket object. Reduced number of CRM individuals from 24k to 3k, improving ElasticSearch
 model and reducing load on RDS and OPC servers during high use time periods.

TECHNOLOGIES

- Proficient Programing Languages: SQL, C#/C++, JAVA, Python, LUA, BASIC
- Machine Learning Systems: Elasticsearch, Apache, SQL, NoSQL, AWS Lambda, Apache Spark
- Cloud Computing Platforms: AWS, Azure, GCP
- AGILE, SCRUM, web design, Flash media, Microsoft Office
- Computer hardware and software including network, antivirus, intrusion detection systems, secure remote access technologies, secure authentication and authorization, Software Development Life Cycle
- Experience with machine learning algorithms in Python: linear regression, logistic regression, decision trees, random forests, support vector machines, Naïve Bayes, neural networks, clustering, dimensionality reduction, and natural language processing (NLP)
- Experience with machine learning models: Classification, Natural Language Processing (NLP), computer vision, recommendation systems, and forecasting

EXPERIENCE

University of California, Davis – Graduate School of Management Systems Administrator 2

October 2022 – Present

- Manage IT ticketing system, triage customer tickets, resolve issues up to capabilities, and provide advanced technical support to Graduate School of Management staff and faculty
- Manage AWS WorkSpaces staff computers, update software, operating system, and provide staff training on use
- Manage software and hardware inventory system for staff and faculty equipment and services
- Develop documentation for new system implementation or existing system updates
- Research and propose system automations to improve small team efficiency

Samuel K. Wolfe

530-638-5831 | wolfesamk@gmail.com | swolfe@ucdavis.edu https://www.linkedin.com/in/wolfesamk | GitHub Portfolio: https://github.com/wolfesamk

- Manage customer service IT operation, implementation and support of secure networks, equipment installation and support, systems administration, and network back-up
- Install specialized hardware and software following federal and state standards
- Create and implement procedures for system operations, support, troubleshooting, plan analysis and recommendations, and customer education
- Provide special project solutions and present key issues, details, and alternatives to both technical and non-technical individuals in an understandable and approachable manner
- Integrate and train new System Engineer I Install Team members

Service Technician

January 2015 – December 2017

- Responded to service requests in an efficient manner while providing customer with arrival times appropriate for the situation
- Applied high quality troubleshooting, fault isolation, repair, and testing to restore customer Pointof-Sale equipment to working order
- Independent operation management for assigning tasks and establishing schedules for regular customer maintenance
- Managed remote supply of work equipment including but not limited to vehicle, tools, spare parts, software, and security devices

McDonalds

Shift Manager

July 2013 – January 2015

- Managed scheduling and training assistance and used interpersonal communication skills and management resources to resolve conflicts
- Daily crew and inventory management, including management over several changes in shift
- Maintained safety and security in accordance with state and federal food and safety standards

EDUCATION

M.S. Business Analytics: Machine Learning, 2024 - California State University Sacramento B.S. Computer Science: Program Engineering, 2020 - Southern New Hampshire University

SKILLS

Team leadership, project management, working in dynamic environments with high security requirements, streamlining processes and reducing waste, ability to rapidly change focus on a moment-to-moment basis to fulfil needs of the team and customers, as well as handling systems in critical states.

REFERENCES

Brian Donnelly – Director of IT, UC Davis – Graduate School of Management (530) 400-6240 **John Burns** – System Engineer IV, Truno (714) 277-7399

Vincent Cavalleri – Staff Services Analyst II, Shasta County HHSA Behavioral Health and Social Services Branch: Children's Services (530) 605-5826